A Guide to the Records of the Clan MacLeod Society USA, 1899-2009
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Records of the Clan MacLeod Society USA 1899-2009
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 41
136 boxes which consist of 118 Hollinger document cases, seven binder cases, six photo boxes, three item boxes, two oversize boxes. 70.84 linear feet
Clan MacLeod Society USA
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The materials in this collection are donated from various members of Clan MacLeod USA.
Biographical Information
The origins of the Clan MacLeod can be traced to a man named Leod, who was born about 1200, and was the son of Olaf the Black, King of Man and the Isles. Leod married the daughter of MacRaild Armuinn about the year 1220. The seat of MacRaild Armuinn was located where Dunvegan Castle stands now. The stronghold of the MacLeods has remained in Dunvegan Castle on the Isle of Skye for the last 800 years. Throughout the centuries MacLeods have been known for their devotion to their chief, the tenacity with which they have maintained Dunvegan Castle, their appreciation for music and Gaelic Lore, their outstanding record in the professions, and their loyalty to one another. For this devotion, perhaps, they are best known for the symbolic motto and crest Hold Fast.
In 1891 Clan MacLeod Societies were founded in both Edinburgh and Glasgow. The families of the MacLeod Chiefs of Dunvegan were closely associated with the clan member societies from the very beginning. Sir Reginald MacLeod of MacLeod, the 27th Chief, and Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod, the 28th Chief, were Presidents of the Society. Beginning in 1951, Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod, the 28th Chief of the Clan MacLeod, undertook a number of tours worldwide, in particular visiting countries known to have clansfolk whose ancestors, relatives or themselves had emigrated from Great Britain. Dame Flora MacLeod visits to the United States in 1952 and 1953 stirred up a surge of interest in the clan and led to the founding of the Clan MacLeod Society, USA, Inc. in 1954. The purpose of the organization was to establish a foundation for charitable, historical and educational pursuits for Clan MacLeod members living in the United States. The objective of that meeting continues to this day, in which the society strengthens fellowship among and encourages the study of the Clan MacLeod history and genealogy.
There are Clan MacLeod Society members in all 50 states, organized into regional societies by geographic area, each with a regional vice president and a national council of officers providing general administrative direction. Twice a year, the society publishes a newsletter with information and updates regarding the clan in the United States. A general meeting is held annually in various regions within the United States. Every four years a North American Gathering is held jointly by Canada and the United States, with the site alternating between the two nations.
The Dunvegan Foundation, which was originally formed to help fund the repair, upkeep, and preservation of Dunvegan Castle, is today the non-profit organization part of Clan MacLeod USA. that works with the Associated Clan MacLeod societies. The Dunvegan Foundation conducts the charitable functions which include promoting the Scottish arts (music, piping and dancing), historical research, scholarships, as well as the preservation of historical places of interest in relation to Clan MacLeod.
The Clan MacLeod Society, USA, Inc. is affiliated with the Associated Clan MacLeod Societies (A.C.M.S), based in Edinburgh, Scotland. The Associated Clan MacLeod Societies is the international coordinating agency for the U.S. and eight other national MacLeod Societies and publishes the Clan MacLeod Magazine. The other national societies are: Australia (est. 1912; re-est. 1951), Canada (est. 1936), England (est. 1937), France (est. 1981), Germany (est. 2003), New Zealand (est. 1954), Scotland (est. 1891), and South Africa (est. 1960). Once every four years, a gathering of all national Clan MacLeod Society members, called a Parliament, occurs at Dunvegan Castle, Scotland.
Present and Past Presidents of the Clan MacLeod Society of the United States, Inc.: John B. MacLeod 2006-; William C. MacLeod 2003-2006; Donald B. MacLeod 2000-2003; Don Mack McLeod 1996-1999; William R. McLeod 1993-1996; Purdy B. McLeod, Jr.1990-1993; Peter M. Norman 1987-1990; William A. MacLeod 1984-1987; Raymond J. McCabe 1983-1984; James S. McLeod 1980-1983; Dr. Alexander C. McLeod 1977-1980; Milton K. McLeod 1972-1977; Charles Anderson McLeod 1970-1972; Anthony M. MacLeod 1966-1970; Dr. Norman W. MacLeod 1964-1966; Lamar W. McLeod 1962-1964; Richard H. McLeod 1960-1962; Sayre MacLeod 1958-1960; Angus McLeod 1956-1958; John H. MacLeod 1954-1956.
Chairmen of the Dunvegan Foundation: John MacLeod Tutterow 2009-
Presidents of the Associated Clan MacLeod Societies: Dr. Malcolm MacLeod, OBE 2006-; Dr. Alexander McLeod 1998-2005;Major Angus MacLeod 1990-1998; Norman MacLeod of Suardal 1986-1990; Major Loudon MacLeod, Royal Marines, retired 1980-1986; Alice, Mrs. MacNab of MacNab 1977-1980; Colonel Colin MacLeod of Glendale 1968-1977; Brigadier Torquil MacLeod 1961-1968.
MacLeod Chiefs of Harris and Dunvegan: 30th Chief, Hugh MacLeod of MacLeod (2007-Present); 29th Chief, John MacLeod of MacLeod (1976-2007); 28th Chief, Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod (1935-1976); 27th Chief, Sir Reginald MacLeod of MacLeod (1929-1935); 26th Chief, Norman Magnus MacLeod (1895-1929); 25th Chief, Norman MacLeod (1835-1895); 24th Chief, John Norman MacLeod (1801-1835); 23rd Chief, Norman MacLeod (The General)(1772-1801); 22nd Chief, Norman MacLeod (The Red Man)(1706-1772); 21st Chief, John (1706-1706); 20th Chief, Norman MacLeod (1699-1706); 19th Chief, Roderick MacLeod (Ruairdh Og)(1693-1699); 18th Chief, Norman MacLeod(Iain Breac/Speckled John) (1664-1693); 17th Chief, Roderick MacLeod, (1649-1664); 16th Chief, John MacLeod (Iain Mor - Big John)(1626-1649); 15th Chief, Sir Roderick (Ruairdh Mor) (1595-1626); 14th Chief, John MacLeod (1590-1595); 13th Chief, William MacLeod (1585-1590); 12th Chief, Norman MacLeod, 1559-1585; 11th Chief, Donald MacLeod (1556-1557); 10th Chief, Mary MacLeod (The Heiress) (1552-1556); 9th Chief, William MacLeod, 1541-1551; 8th Chief, Alexander MacLeod (Alasdair Crotach - Alexander the Humpback) (1500-1541); 7th Chief, William Dubh MacLeod (1442-1500); 6th Chief, John MacLeod (Iain Borb - John the Turbulent) (1402-1442); 5th Chief, William Cleireach MacLeod (William the Clerk) (1392-1402); 4th Chief, John MacLeod (Iain Ciar) (1370-1392); 3rd Chief, Malcolm MacLeod (built Dunvegan Castle)(1320-1370); 2nd Chief Norman (Tormod) (1280- c.1320); 1st Chief, Leod (c. 1266-1280).
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials related to Clan MacLeod USA, the Dunvegan Foundation, the Associated Clan MacLeod Societies, and the international societies of Clan MacLeod. Materials include documents, correspondence, newsletters, magazines, photographs, reel to reel audio tapes, and computer files. These items date from the late 1800s to 2009.
Arrangement
This collection is broken down into the following series: I. Clan Mac Leod USA; II. Personal Correspondence; III. Dunvegan Foundation; IV. Cultural and Educational Resources; V. Publications; VI. Associated Clan MacLeod Societies (A.C.M.S.); VII. Clan MacLeod National Societies; VIII. Other Scottish-Related Groups, Foundations, and Clans; IX. Events; X. Photographs; XI. Electronic Media; XII. Artifacts.
Contents List
- Clan MacLeod USA 1952-2009.
  This series is divided into twenty-five sub-series of administrative documents, records, and items pertaining to the Clan MacLeod Society of the United States. Sub-series A: Annual General Meeting; Sub-series B: Awards; Sub-series C: Brochures and Bulletins; Sub-series D: Committees/Councils; Sub-series E: Constitution, By-Laws, and Incorporation; Sub-series F: Correspondence; Sub-series G: Council Meetings; Sub-series H: Clan MacLeod Dancers; Sub-series I: Financial and Legal; Sub-series J: Handbooks and Manuals; Sub-series K: Membership; Sub-series L: Minutes and Agendas; Sub-series M: Newsletter; Sub-series N: North American Gathering; Sub-series O: Old Dominion University and Archives; Sub-series P: Presidents; Sub-series Q: Projects-Migration project in regard to Clan MacLeod USA; Sub-series R: Projects-Miscellaneous; Sub-series S: Regional Societies; Sub-series T: Reports; Sub-series U: Reports-Annual; Sub-series V: Reports-Membership Secretary; Sub-series W: Reports-Secretary; Sub-series X: Reports-Treasurer; Sub-series Y: Miscellaneous. This series is arranged in chronological and alphabetical order.
  - Annual General Meeting 1955-2003
    - History and background of Clan MacLeod USA Annual General Meetings (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Planning for Annual General Meeting (Box-folder 1:2)
    - New York City 1955 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - New York City 1956 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - New York City 1957 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - New York City 1958 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - New York City 1959 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - New York City 1960 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - New York City 1961 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - New York City 1962 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - New York City 1963 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - New York City 1964 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - New York City 1965 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - New York City 1966 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - New York City 1967 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - New York City 1968 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - New York City 1969 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - New York City 1970 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - New York City 1971 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - New York City 1972 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Washington D.C. 1974 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Nashville, Tennessee 1975 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Cornwall, Ontario (1st Joint North American Clan Gathering) 1976 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - New York City 1977 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Princeton, New Jersey 1978 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Dunedin, Florida (typo on meeting agenda has the year 1977) 1979 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Dearborn, Michigan 1980 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Seattle, Washington 1981 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Hampton, Virginia 1982 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Albuquerque, New Mexico 1983 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Nova Scotia 1984 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Longbeach, California 1985 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Charleston, South Carolina (I) 1986 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Charleston, South Carolina (II) 1986 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Williamsburg, Virginia 1987 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Chicago, Illinois 1988 (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Salt Lake City, Utah 1989 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Proposed schedule of annual general meeting locations 1990 (Box-folder 2:12)
    - Atlanta, Georgia 1990 (Box-folder 2:13)
    - San Francisco, California 1991 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Vancouver, British Columbia 1992 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Houston, Texas 1993 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Dunvegan, Scotland 1994 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Braintree, Massachusetts 1995 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - West Point, New York 1996 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Taos, New Mexico 1997 (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Dunvegan, Scotland (information and proxy votes) 1998 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Bowling Green, Kentucky 2003 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Awards
    - Awards Committee Reports (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Clan MacLeod award of appreciation to Laura Margaret MacLeod August, 1994 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Clan MacLeod award of appreciation to Laura Margaret MacLeod July, 1996 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Clansperson of the year awards (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Dame Flora MacLeod of MacLeod trophy for first piper, Grandfather Mountain Games (Box-folder 3:14)
    - MacCrimmon Quaich award (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Piping awards (Box-folder 3:16)
    - Scottish American Military Society (SAMS) award (Box-folder 3:17)
    - Service awards program (Box-folder 3:18)
    - What Clan MacLeod Society Membership Means to Me March 1963 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Brochures and Bulletins
    - Clan MacLeod Society of America brochure 1957 (Box-folder 3:20)
    - New-sheet July 28, 1964 (Box-folder 3:21)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of America brochure 1965 (Box-folder 3:22)
    - Clan MacLeod Society USA brochures 1970s (Box-folder 3:23)
    - The Skye Line-A newsletter for junior members of the Clan MacLeod Society, USA Spring, 1974 (Box-folder 3:24)
    - Clan MacLeod Society USA brochures 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 3:25)
    - Lands of MacLeod pamphlet 1998 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Committees/Councils
    - Committee members (?) undated (Box-folder 3:27)
    - Council committee listings, undated (Box-folder 3:28)
    - Cultural and Educational Committee, undated (Box-folder 3:29)
    - Operational organization of committees, undated (Box-folder 3:30)
    - Officers 1958 (Box-folder 3:31)
    - Officers 1959 (Box-folder 3:32)
    - Officers 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3:33)
    - Clan Council 1977 (Box-folder 3:34)
    - Clan Council 1979 (Box-folder 3:35)
    - Clan Council 1980 (Box-folder 3:36)
    - Executive Committee 1980 (Box-folder 3:37)
    - Nominating Committee 1980 (Box-folder 3:38)
    - Clan Council 1981 (Box-folder 3:39)
    - Advisory Council 1982 (Box-folder 3:40)
    - Clan Council 1982 (Box-folder 3:41)
    - Nominations for Clan Council 1982 (Box-folder 3:42)
    - Membership Committee 1983-1984 (Box-folder 3:43)
    - Nominations for Clan Council (?) 1983 (Box-folder 3:44)
    - Clan Council 1984 (Box-folder 3:45)
    - Planning Session Committee 1984 (Box-folder 3:46)
    - Draft Nominations for Clan Council 1985 (Box-folder 3:47)
    - Migration Committee, Income/Expenditures (estimate) January-October 1985 (Box-folder 3:48)
    - Council Listing (?) 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3:49)
    - Youth Members Committee 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3:50)
    - Society Council 1989-1990 (Box-folder 3:51)
    - Committee Appointments 1992-1993 (Box-folder 3:52)
    - Nominating Committee (?) 1993 (Box-folder 3:53)
    - Activities Committee Report November 30, 1995 (Box-folder 3:54)
    - Gathering Committee 1996 (Box-folder 3:55)
    - Clan Council 1999 (Box-folder 3:56)
    - Autumn Clan Committee 2001 (Box-folder 3:57)
    - Executive Committee 2003 (Box-folder 3:58)
  - Constitution, By-Laws, and Incorporation
    - Clan MacLeod Society information (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Original by-laws? (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Society by-laws (undated) (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Proposed by-laws and position descriptions (undated) (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Organization of Clan MacLeod (undated) (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Certificate of Incorporation 1954 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of America-Constitution as revised 1973 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of America-Constitution as revised 1974 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Certificate of amendments of the certificate of incorporation of Clan MacLeod Society of America, Inc. under section 803 if the Not-For-Profit Corporation Law of the State of New York 1977 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Constitution revision items September 17, 1979 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Clan MacLeod Society of America-Constitution as revised and as amended 1974, 1979, 1980 (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Proposed constitution and council considerations 1985 (Box-folder 4:12)
    - Certificate of Incorporation January 17, 1987 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Constitution of the Clan MacLeod Society USA, Inc. adopted at the Annual General Meeting at Williamsburg, Virginia March 27, 1987 (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Corporate resolution for the account of Clan MacLeod Society, USA, Inc. January 28, 1988 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Clan MacLeod Certificate of Incorporation issues 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Proposed revisions and draft: Constitution of the Clan MacLeod Society, USA, Inc. 1992 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Suggestions for by-laws, council members, dues (Box-folder 4:18)
    - Certificate of incorporation from the state of South Carolina January 28, 1983 (Box Oversize Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence 1952-1953 (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Correspondence (I) 1954 (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Correspondence (I) 1955 (Box-folder 4:21)
    - Correspondence (II) 1955 (Box-folder 4:22)
    - Correspondence (II) 1954 (Box Box 5 (Binder Case))
    - Correspondence (I) 1956 (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Correspondence (II) 1956 (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Correspondence (III) 1956 (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Correspondence (I) 1957 (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Correspondence (II) 1957 (Box-folder 6:5)
    - Correspondence 1958 (Box-folder 6:6)
    - Correspondence 1959 (Box-folder 6:7)
    - Correspondence 1960 (Box-folder 6:8)
    - Correspondence 1961 (Box-folder 6:9)
    - Correspondence 1962 (Box-folder 6:10)
    - Correspondence 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Correspondence 1965 (Box-folder 6:12)
    - Correspondence (IV) 1956 (Box Box 7 (Binder Case))
    - Correspondence 1966 (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Correspondence 1967 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Correspondence 1968 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Correspondence 1970 (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Correspondence 1971 (Box-folder 8:6)
    - Correspondence 1972 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Correspondence 1973-1974 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Correspondence 1978 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - Correspondence 1979 (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Correspondence 1980 (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Correspondence 1981 (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Correspondence 1982 (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Correspondence 1983 (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Correspondence 1984 (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Correspondence 1985 (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Correspondence 1986 (Box-folder 9:4)
    - Correspondence (I) 1987 (Box-folder 9:5)
    - Correspondence (II) 1987 (Box-folder 9:6)
    - Correspondence (I) 1988 (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Correspondence (II) 1988 (Box-folder 9:8)
    - Correspondence (I) 1989 (Box-folder 10:1)
    - Correspondence (II) 1989 (Box-folder 10:2)
    - Correspondence (I) 1990 (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Correspondence (II) 1990 (Box-folder 10:4)
    - Correspondence (I) 1991 (Box-folder 10:5)
    - Correspondence (II) 1991 (Box-folder 10:6)
    - Correspondence (III) 1991 (Box-folder 10:7)
    - Correspondence 1992 (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Correspondence (I) 1993 (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Correspondence (II) 1993 (Box-folder 11:3)
    - Correspondence (I) 1994 (Box-folder 11:4)
    - Correspondence (II) 1994 (Box-folder 11:5)
    - Correspondence (I) 1995 (Box-folder 11:6)
    - Correspondence (II) 1995 (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Correspondence (I) 1996 (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Correspondence (II) 1996 (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Correspondence 1997 (Box-folder 12:2)
    - Correspondence 1998 (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Correspondence 1999 (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Correspondence 2000- (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Correspondence-undated (Box-folder 12:6)
  - Council Meetings
    - Council Meetings 1965 (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Council Meetings 1966 (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Council Meetings 1968 (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Council Meetings 1969 (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Council Meetings 1970 (Box-folder 13:5)
    - Council Meetings 1971 (Box-folder 13:6)
    - Council Meetings 1972 (Box-folder 13:7)
    - Council Meetings 1973 (Box-folder 13:8)
    - Council Meetings 1974 (Box-folder 13:9)
    - Council Meetings 1975 (Box-folder 13:10)
    - Council Workshop 1977 (Box-folder 13:11)
    - Council Meetings 1978 (Box-folder 13:12)
    - Council Meetings 1979 (Box-folder 13:13)
    - Council Meetings 1980 (Box-folder 13:14)
    - Council Meetings 1981 (Box-folder 13:15)
    - Council Meetings 1982 (Box-folder 13:16)
    - Council Meetings 1983 (Box-folder 13:17)
    - Council Meetings 1984 (Box-folder 13:18)
    - Council Meetings 1985 (Box-folder 13:19)
    - Council Meetings 1987 (Box-folder 13:20)
    - Council Meetings 1988 (Box-folder 13:21)
    - Council Meetings 1989 (Box-folder 14:1)
    - Council Meetings 1990 (Box-folder 14:2)
    - Council Meetings 1991 (Box-folder 14:3)
    - Council Meetings 1992 (Box-folder 14:4)
    - Council Meetings 1993 (Box-folder 14:5)
    - Council Meetings 1994 (Box-folder 14:6)
    - Council Meetings 1995 (Box-folder 14:7)
    - Council Meetings 1996 (Box-folder 14:8)
    - Council Meetings 1997 (Box-folder 14:9)
    - Council Meetings 2003 (Box-folder 14:10)
    - Council Meetings 2004 (Box-folder 14:11)
  - Clan MacLeod Dancers
    - Clan MacLeod Dancers correspondence 1985, 1988-1990, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 14:12)
    - MacLeod Dance and Entertainment Troupe: Elks-Shrine-Knights of Columbus Night April 17, 1984 (Box-folder 14:13)
    - Clan MacLeod Dancers information (Box-folder 14:14)
    - Clan MacLeod Dancers;Magical Misty Tour; and Caper (Box-folder 14:15)
    - The Dances of a Island Clan-book advertisements (Box-folder 14:16)
    - Red Ghillies-A Newsletter for the Clan MacLeod Dancers 1991, 1993 (Box-folder 14:17)
    - Goals-Chair for Dancing (undated) (Box-folder 14:18)
    - Chair for Dancing report (undated) (Box-folder 14:19)
    - Annual Report-Chair for Dancing 1989 (Box-folder 14:20)
    - Special Report-Chair for Dancing 1989 (Box-folder 14:21)
    - Annual Report-Chair for Dancing 1990 (Box-folder 14:22)
    - Special Report on the Chair for Dancing November 30, 1990 (Box-folder 14:23)
    - Report on Dancing: Associated Clan MacLeod Societies & Alasdair Crotach 1992 (Box-folder 14:24)
    - Report from the Chair of Dancing June 1993 (Box-folder 15:1)
    - Report on Dancing: Associated Clan MacLeod Societies & Alasdair Crotach Committee June 1993 (Box-folder 15:2)
    - Report from the Chair of Dancing December 1993 (Box-folder 15:3)
    - Report from the Chair of Dancing August 1994 (Box-folder 15:4)
    - Scottish Country Dancing Group (predecessor to the Clan MacLeod Dancers) 1964 (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Financial and Legal
    - Application for recognition of exemption 1983 (Box-folder 15:6)
    - Bookkeeping (Box-folder 15:7)
    - Check register November 17, 1994 (Box-folder 15:8)
    - Clan expenses 1950s-1990s (Box-folder 15:9)
    - Financial statistics 1980s (Box-folder 15:10)
    - First National Bank of Morgantown, deposited checks 1985-1986 (Box-folder 15:11)
    - Foundation and Society 1980 (?) (Box-folder 15:12)
    - I.R.S./tax correspondence (Box-folder 15:13)
    - Invoices and receipts (Box-folder 15:14)
    - Last will and testament of Andrew MacLeod 1974 (Box-folder 15:15)
    - Operating Account Journal 1999 (Box-folder 15:16)
    - Postal service certification 1974 (Box-folder 15:17)
    - Proper Book of Accounts (Box-folder 15:18)
    - Regulation CC (Box-folder 15:19)
    - Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax 1956-1979 (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax 1980-1982, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 16:2)
    - Royal Bank of Scotland correspondence 1992 (Box-folder 16:3)
    - State of South Carolina-Return of Organization Exempt From Income Tax 1987-1991 (Box-folder 16:4)
    - Tax status for Clan MacLeod (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Handbooks and Manuals
    - Member's Handbook: Clan MacLeod Society USA 1980 (Box-folder 16:6)
    - Member's Handbook: Clan MacLeod Society USA 1984 (Box-folder 16:7)
    - Printing bids for members handbook 1993 (Box-folder 16:8)
    - Revisions to handbooks (Box-folder 16:9)
    - Job descriptions (Box-folder 16:10)
    - Leadership and administration (Box-folder 16:11)
    - Leadership and administration (Box-folder 16:12)
  - Membership
    - Annual dues notice-envelopes and cards (Box-folder 16:13)
    - Applications requests (Box-folder 16:14)
    - Change of address poem (Box-folder 16:15)
    - Membership correspondence 1956 (Box-folder 16:16)
    - Membership correspondence 1960-61, 1963, 1969 (Box-folder 16:17)
    - Membership correspondence 1978, 1986, 1988 (Box-folder 16:18)
    - Membership correspondence 1991 (Box-folder 16:19)